Guide to the Florencio Asenjo Collection, 1945-2013 UA.90.F105
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Florencio Asenjo Collection
1945-2013
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Asenjo, Florencio
UA.90.F105
7.25 Linear Feet
The collection documents the musical career of Florencio Asenjo, and contains manuscript sketches and first and final versions of all of the composer's musical output, mostly for orchestra or chamber ensemble. In addition, correspondence, audio recordings, and clippings from the musical press are included.
Biography
Born in Buenos Aires, Argentina in 1926, Asenjo was a mathematician who came from Argentina to the United States in 1958. He was professor on the faculty at several American universities, including Georgetown, Southern Illinois, and the University of Pittsburgh, where he was associate professor of mathematics from 1963 to 2010. Asenjo also had intellectual interests in other areas such as philosophy—especially phenomenology—art history, aesthetics, and especially music. During his youth Mr. Asenjo studied piano, composition, and conducting with the Spanish composer Jaime Pahissa (1880-1969) in Buenos Aires.
Asenjo´s musical output is principally in symphonic repertoire, and has been performed by orchestras and musical ensembles like the Eastman Philharmonic, Eastman Wind Ensemble, U.S. Air Force Band, American University Orchestra, La Plata Symphony Orchestra, Slovak National Symphony Orchestra, the Bulgarian Philharmonia, and the Warsaw National Philharmonic Orchestra. Despite some commercial recordings made in the last ten years by Albany Records, the music of Florencio G. Asenjo is relatively unknown to researchers, musicians, and audiences in general.
In his music, Asenjo tries to avoid overt repetition, which he considers "overwhelming in Western music". Indeed, according to his own words, he does not "want to do repetition for repetition's sake". As a result, he experiments using the relationship between two types of contrasting themes that are commonly found in symphonies and concertos.
According to the composer, these two themes are connected in intent and aesthetic rather than in content. Thus, Asenjo saw in this dialectic contrast the opportunity to create chains of themes in his music that are aesthetically connected, retaining continuity and atmosphere. This particular approach was labeled maximalism by Asenjo, which can be described as a high density of content in constant change. Asenjo passed away in 2013 in Pittsburgh.
Scope: The collection contains sketches and the first and final versions of all of Asenjo's musical output, all for orchestra or chamber ensemble. Included are performance parts and the transparencies used to produce the parts. In addition, Asenjo's vast correspondence with other composers and conductors, among them Igor Stravinsky, Jaime Pahissa, and Ernesto Halffter, among others. Audio recordings, on reel-to-reel tapes and cassettes, by various orchestras and ensembles are also included, along with newspaper clippings of reviews of these concerts.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in six series: Series 1 includes music compositions that are dated and Series 2, those that are undated on the manuscripts. Series 3 includes drafts and final printed versions of articles written by Asenjo, mostly on musical topics. Series 4 includes documents on Asenjo's interaction with music publishers, newspaper articles and clippings, and contracts. Series 5 includes correspondence with other composers and conductors, documents that pertain to Asenjo's travels, and photographic images. Series 6 includes reel-to-reel and cassette tape recordings of Asenjo's works by various orchestras and ensembles, and radio interviews.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Julian Asenjo on March 24, 2014.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Scope and Content Notes
The collection contains sketches and the first and final versions of all of Asenjo's musical output, all for orchestra or chamber ensemble. Included are performance parts and the transparencies used to produce the parts. In addition, Asenjo's vast correspondence with other composers and conductors, among them Igor Stravinsky, Jaime Pahissa, and Ernesto Halffter, among others. Audio recordings, on reel-to-reel tapes and cassettes, by various orchestras and ensembles are also included, along with newspaper clippings of reviews of these concerts.
Music -- Manuscripts; Piano music; Chamber music -- Scores and parts; Orchestral music; Music -- 20th century; Composers -- Argentina; Asenjo, Florencio
- Dated Compositions, 1945-2011; I.
  - Preludio en Mi b Mayor; [Prelude in E Flat Major], 1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Variaciones Sobre un Tema de [Jaime] Pahissa; [Variations on a Theme of Pahissa], 1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Scope and Contents
    On page 9: "17/10/1945". Theme and five variations. On the back of page 9: "Hussein Husliya"
  - Suite of Pieces for Piano, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Instrument: Piano
    I. Retrato [Portrait]; II. Corceles Féricos; III. Tarde de Invierno [Winter Afternoon]; IV: Cántiga para una Niña Ruborosa [cantiga for a Blushed Girl]; and V. Pequeña Fuga [Litle Fugue]. Although the title "Suite" is not indicated, the numbers on the first caption of each piece [in blue pencil] suggest an order. Date on first page: "9-1946" and last page"1946 (Junio) [1946, June]". Pasteover on mm. 8 and 9 of "Tarde de Invierno". Manuscript signed by the composer
  - Allegro sketch, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Work dedicated to the composer's father. Date on first manuscript page: "28/10/1946."
  - Allegro manuscript, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Symphony for Strings [Sinfonia para Instrumentos de Cuerda], 1948; 1.
    Instruments: String orchestra: 2 Violins, Viola, Cello, and Double bass
    Dates on the first page of the manuscript: composed between November 1946 and August 1948, premiered on October 11, 1953, El Teatro Argentino, La Plata, Argentina. Other performances: June 3, 1954, State Radio Symphony, Buenos Aires (conductor Bruno Bandini); February 26, 1960, The American University Orchestra, Washington D.C. (conductor: George Steiner).
    - Drafts of Manuscript (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Full score manuscript (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Full score transparencies (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Ozalid-printed score (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Ozalid-printed parts transparencies (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Ozalid-printed parts copies (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Other related materials (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Orquesta Sinfonica de la Radio del Estado (LRA), Buenos Aires, June 3, 1954; 1.
      - The American University Orchestra, Washington D.C. [mimeograph], February 26, 1960; 2.
  - Concierto para Instrumentos de Viento; [Concert for Wind Instruments], 1950; 2.
    Instruments: Piccolo, 2 Flutes, 2 Oboes, English Horn, 2 B-flat Clarinets, B-flat Bass Clarinet, B-Flat Soprano Saxophone (or Clarinet), 2 Bassoons, Contrabassoon, 2 Horns in F, 2 Trumpets in B-flat, 2 Trombones, and Tuba.
    Date at the end of movement II: 19 de Mayo de 1950. Premiered in January 1960 by the U.S. Air Force Band (Conductor: Harry Meuser), Washington D.C. Other performances: April 30, 1964, Eastman Wind Ensemble (Conductor: A. Clyde Roller); February 18, 1966, Brevard College Orchestra; November 23, 1975, Duquesne University Symphony Band; February 23, 1984, Carnegie Mellon Wind Ensemble.
    - Full score manuscript (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Full score transparencies (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Copies from transparencies (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Parts (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Other related material (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, 1952, 1960-1964; 1.
      - Performance by Carnegie-Mellon Wind Ensemble, 1984; 2.
  - Danza de los Secretarios [Dance of the Secretaries], 1961; 3.
    Instruments: Orchestra: 2 Flutes, 2 Oboes, 2 Bb Clarinets, 2 Bassoons, 2 Trumpets in Bb, 2 Trombones, 2 Violin, Viola, Cello, Double bass, and Timpani.
    This piece was the first of a series of sketches based on some fables by Franz Kafka. Notes on first sketch: "5 August, 1960". Notes on second sketch: "24 de Septiembre 1960." Duration indicated on second draft´s last page: 5 min, 30 sec. Premiered on April 27, 1965 by the Eastman Philharmonia (Conductor: A. Clyde Roller) in Rochester, New York. Other performances: April 8, 1976, Duquesne University Symphony (Conductor: Bernard Goldberg). This work was selected to be presented at the 35th Festival of American Music at the University of Rochester.
    - Sketches, August 4, September 24, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Full score manuscripts (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Full score transparencies (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Ozalid-printed full score (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Parts transparencies (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Ozalid-printed parts (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Other related documents (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Program of the "Thirty-Fifth Annual Festival of American Music" at the Institute of American Music and the Eastman School of Music at the University of Rochester, April 27-30, 1965; 1.
      - Correspondence with people and institutions, 1963-1995; 2.
  - Effusions: A Symphony of Transitions, 1967; 4.
    Instruments: Orchestra: Flute, Oboe, Bb Clarinet, Trumpets in C, Trombone, 2 Violins, Viola, Cello, Double bass, Timpani.
    I. La Joie de Vivre, II. Convictions; III. Fiestas. Two wind instruments indicated in the full score manuscript. However, in the printed score only one wind instrument appears. Date on the first page of the draft of "La joie de vivre": Dec. 2, 1967.
    - Sketch of full score manuscript (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Full score manuscript (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Full score manuscript (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Printed full score (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Printed Parts (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cavalcade of Cubes, 1969; 5.
    Instruments: Orchestra: Piccolo, Flute, Oboe, English Horn, B-flat Clarinet, Bass Clarinet, Bassoon, Contra Bassoon, Horn in F, Trumpet in B-flat, Trombone, Tuba, Timpani, 2 Violins, Viola, Cello, and Double bass.
    Date on first page of sketch: "XI-9-67". Premiered on April 27, 1976 by Duquesne University Symphony Orchestra (Conductor: Bernard Goldberg) in Pittsburgh.
    - Sketch (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Full score manuscript (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Full score transparencies (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Ozalid-printed full score (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Parts transparencies (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Ozalid-printed parts (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Other related documents (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Letter from Jennifer Bilfield, Executive Director of the National Orchestra Association, July 20, 1989; 1.
      - Correspondence with people in institutions, 1970-1974; 2.
  - Symphony No. 2 [Instrumental Dialogues], 1979; 6.
    Instruments: Orchestra: Flute, Oboe, B-flat Clarinet, Bassoon, Horn in F, Trumpet in C, 2 Violins, Viola, Cello, Double bass, and Timpani.
    Name differs in print score and parts: "Instrumental Dialogues: A Symphony in Four Movements". Date on the first page of the manuscript: "July 22, 1977". Work composed between January 1, 1977 and April 29, 1979 [with a pause of ten months]. Premiered on June 5, 1981 by the Duquesne University Symphony Orchestra (Conductor: Bernard Goldberg). Other performances: February 14, 1983, University of Pittsburgh Orchestra (Conductor: Grover Wilkins).
    - Full score manuscript (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Copyist manuscript (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Printed full scores (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Parts manuscripts (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Ozalid-printed parts (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Other related documents (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Paper with dates of composition process, 1.
      - Correspondence, 2.
  - Crystallizations: A Symphony in the Nascent State [Symphony No. 3], 1989; 7.
    Instruments: Orchestra: Flute, Oboe, B-flat Clarinet, Bassoon, Horn if F, Trumpet in C, Timpani, 2 Violins, Viola, Cello, and Double bass.
    Named as Symphony No. 3 on full score manuscript. Contents: I. Lento; II. Andante; III. Moderato. Annotations in full score manuscript: "Mar 4, 82" [on p. 1], "Feb. 21, 87" [on p. 41] and "Estoril, August 15, 1987" [on p. 119]. This work was composed over eight years. According to the notes of the composer, the first draft was written between "July 25, 1980 and April 29, 1981;" the second draft was written between "December 10, 1981 and March 2, 1982;" the final draft was written between "March 4, 1982 and August 15, 1987" [the work was interrupted between April 30, 1982 and September 7, 1986].
    - Full score manuscript (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Final full score (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Master copy of printed full score (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Printed full score (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Printed full score (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Parts (chopped from full score) (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Master copy of parts (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Spiral-bound parts (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Other related documents (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Purpose, 1.
      - Papers with dates of composition process, 2.
      - Receipts of copies and binding of score and parts, 3.
  - Concerto for Orchestra, 2010-2011; 8.
    Instruments: Orchestra: Flute, Oboe, Clarinet in B-flat, Bassoon, Horn in F, Trumpet in C, Trombone, 2 Violins, Viola, Cello, Double bass.
    Three movements. Different dates: "2010" [on manila folder that contains full score manuscript], "revised 10/23/2011" on p. 1 of printed [transposed] full score; "revised 10/16/2011" on printed parts.
    - Full score manuscript (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Printed [transposed] full score (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Printed parts (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Undated Compositions, II.
  - A Diptych of Lord Dunsany's Tales, 1.
    Instruments: Orchestra: solo Violin, Flute, Oboe, English horn, Clarinet in B-flat, Bass clarinet in B-flat, Bassoon, Horn in F, Trumpet in C, 2 Violins, Viola, Cello, and Double bass.
    Two sections divided in several movements: Section I. Carcasole: I. When the world was fairier[sic]; II. The harp; III. Turning aside the dooms of fate; IV. The deeps of the forest; V. The music of bells. Section II. In the land before time: VI. The mists before the beginning; VII. Without light; VIII. The pace of things: many times or nor time. Notes on first page of printed [Transposed] score "11/28/11."
    - Full score manuscript (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Printed [transposed] full score (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - printed parts (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Angels Dancing on a Pin, 2.
    Instruments: Orchestra: 2 Flutes, 2 Oboes, 2 Bb Clarinets, 2 Bassoons, Timpani, 2 Violins, Viola, Cello, and Double bass.
    Note in the p. 40 of printed full score: "duration 6'46''"
    - Full score manuscript (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Full score manuscript (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Printed full score (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Printed full score, director score (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Printed parts (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - A Thousand and One Nights: Impressions for Clarinet and Orchestra, 3.
    Instruments: Orchestra: Flute, Oboe, B-flat Clarinet, Bassoon, Horn in F, Trumpet in C, Trombone, 2 Violins, Viola, Cello, and Double bass.
    I. The thrall [sic] of love; II. The hermits; III. The flea and the mouse; IV. The ebony horse; V. The angel of death; VI. City of brass; VII. The lovers of Medina; VIII. The spider and the wind; IX. The quintessence of things; X. Maruf, the cobbler.
    [Although the title of this work suggests that there is a clarinet soloist, there is no part for solo clarinet.]
    - Manuscript score (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Printed full scores (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Printed parts (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - A Throw of the Dice, 4.
    Instruments: Orchestra: Flute, Oboe, B-flat Clarinet, Bassoon, Trumpet in C, Trombone, 2 Violins, Viola, Cello, Double bass, Timpani.
    - Full score manuscript (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Full score manuscript copies (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Printed full score (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Printed parts (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Basile's Pentameron: Concerto Grosso A Cinque, 5.
    Instruments: Orchestra: Flute, Oboe, B-flat Clarinet, Bassoon, Horn in F, Trumpet in C, Trombone, 2 solo Violins, solo Viola, solo Cello, Cello, Double bass, and Timpani.
    I. Cat Cinderella; II. The old woman discovered; III. The large louse, the mouse and the cricket; IV. Pride punished; V. End of tales of tales.
    - Full score manuscript (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Copy of the full score (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Printed full score (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Printed full score (corrected) (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Printed parts (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - El Gran Teatro del Mundo [The Great Theater of the World], 6.
    - Full score manuscript (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Instruments: Chamber Orchestra: Flute, English horn in F, Bass clarinet in B-flat, Tenor Saxophone in B-flat, Violin, Viola, and Double bass.
      Contents: I. Waltz interrupted; II. Solemn march; III. Requiem; IV. La joie de vivre; V. Rain; VI. Dialogue of time and space; VII. Venus playing; VIII. Transfigured moment; IX. Pierrot solaire.
    - Printed [transposed] full score (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Figures Taking Form, 7.
    Instruments: Orchestra: Flute, Oboe, B-flat Clarinet, Bassoon, Horn in F, Trumpet in C, Timpani, 2 Violins, Viola, Cello, and Double bass.
    - Ozalid-copy full score manuscript (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Full score manuscript copies (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Printed full score (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Printed parts (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Images for Clarinet and Orchestra, 8.
    Instruments: Orchestra and solo Clarinet: solo Clarinet, Flute, Oboe, Bassoon, Trumpet in C, Trombone, 2 Violins, Violin, Cello, and Double bass.
    Notes: Contents: I. Dulcinea's garden; II. Scherezade's dance; III. Children's dreams; IV. The great cemeteries under the moon; V. Night in the Alhambra. Note on p. 70 full score: "Duration 23'34"
    - Full score manuscript (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Full score manuscript (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Printed full score (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Printed full score (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Printed parts (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Gleanings From the World of Lafcadio Hearn, 9.
    - Full score manuscript (Box 17, Folder 2)
      Instruments: Orchestra: Flute, Oboe, Clarinet in B-flat, Bassoon, Violin, Viola, Cello, and Double bass.
      Contents: I. A wish fulfilled; II. Story of a fly; III. Of a promise broken; IV. Of a mirror and bell; V. Ultimate questions; VI. Beauty is memory; VII. The reconciliation.
    - Printed [transposed] full score (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Glimpses, 10.
    Instruments: Orchestra: Flute, Oboe, B-flat Clarinet, Bassoon, Trumpet in C, Tenor Trombone, Timpani, 2 Violins, Viola, Cello, Double bass.
    Contents: I. Dialogues on Peace; II. At the Art Gallery; III. Glimpses of Childhood; IV. Walking by the River.
    - Full score manuscript (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Full score manuscript (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Printed full score (first page missing) (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Printed parts (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Glimpses at Borges Universe: Three Impressions for Violin and Orchestra, 11.
    Instruments: Orchestra and solo Violin: solo Violin, Flute, Oboe, Clarinet in B-flat, Bassoon, Horn in F, Trumpet in C, Trombone, Violin 2, Viola, Cello, Double bass.
    Notes: Contents: I. The Garden of king Paths; II. The Aleph; III. Labyrinths. On p. 1 of printed [Transposed] score "8/12/11."
    - Full score manuscript (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Printed full [revised] score (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Printed parts (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Palm of the Hand Tales, 12.
    Instruments: Orchestra: Flute, Oboe, B-flat Clarinet, Bassoon, Horn in F, Trumpet in C, Trombone, 2 Violins, Viola, Cello, Double bass.
    Contents: I. A sunny place; II. The girl who approached the fire; III. The grasshopper and the bell cricket; IV. A childs viewpoint; V. Goldfish on the roof; VI. The rooster and the dancing girl; VII. The wife of the autumn wind; VIII. Immortality; IX. The white horse; 10. Gleanings from snow country.
    - Full score manuscript (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Copy of full score manuscript (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Printed full score with corrections (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Printed full score (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Printed parts (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Passion and Apotheosis: A Symphony in Two Movements, 13.
    Instruments: Orchestra: Flute, Oboe, B-flat Clarinet, Bassoon, Trumpet in C, Trombone, 2 Violins, Viola, Cello, Double bass, and Timpani.
    - Full score manuscript (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Full score manuscript (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Printed full score (first page missing) (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Printed parts (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Resonances: A Symphony for Solo Players and Orchestra, 14.
    Instruments: Orchestra: Flute (Soloist movement I), Oboe, B-flat Clarinet (Soloist movement III), Bassoon (Soloist movement IV), Horn in F (Soloist movement II), Trumpet in C (Soloist movement V), Trombone, 2 Violins (Violin Soloist in movements II and IV), Viola (Soloist movement III), Cello (Soloist movements I and V), Double bass, and Timpani.
    I. Andante; II. Adagio; III. Allegro; IV. Largo; V. Moderato.
    - Full score manuscript (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Full score manuscript (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Printed full score (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Printed parts (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Scherzo and Trio, 15.
    Instruments: String trio: Violin, Viola and Cello.
    Title on draft: "Canon a tres voces". Title on full score manuscript written in blue ink: "Trío de Violín, Viola y Violonchello: 2". Notes on p. 1 of full score manuscript "$11.05 1327 16th NW Apt 9 DU 7-9360"
    - Draft (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Full score manuscript (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Parts transparencies (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Printed parts (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Sinfonia Concertante [Symphony Concertante], 16.
    Instruments: Orchestra: Flute, Oboe, English Horn, B-flat Clarinet, Bassoon, Horn in F, 2 Violins, Viola, Cello, Double bass, and Timpani.
    Contents: I. Moderato; II. Andante; III. Andante.
    - Manuscript score (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Printed [transposed] score (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Printed parts (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Tearings, 17.
    Contents: I. Prelude; II. Variations; III. Sketches; IV. Danza
    - Full score manuscript (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Full score manuscript (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Printed parts (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - The Batrachomyomachia, or The Battle of the Frogs and the Mice, 18.
    Instruments: Orchestra: Flute, Oboe, B-flat Clarinet, Bassoon, Horn in F, Trumpet, Trombone, Timpani, 2 Violins, Viola, cello, Double bass.
    - Full score manuscript (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Copy of full score manuscript (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Printed full score (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Printed full score (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Printed parts (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - The Birth of Venus, 19.
    - Full score manuscript (Box 22, Folder 1)
      Instruments: Orchestra: Flute, Oboe, English Horn, Clarinet in B-flat, Bass Clarinet in B-flat, Bassoon, 2 Violins, Viola, Cello, and Double bass.
      Full score indicates solos for: Flute, Violin, Viola, Cello, and Double bass.
    - Printed [transposed] full score (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - The Odyssey, 20.
    Instruments: Orchestra: Flute, Oboe, English Horn. B-flat Clarinet, Bassoon, Horn in F, Trumpet in C, 2 Violins, Viola, Cello, and Double bass.
    Contents: I. Atlántida; II. Sirens; III. Hades; IV. Circe; V. Nausicaa; VI. Cyclops; VII. Exultation
    - Full score manuscript (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Full score manuscript (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Printed manuscript (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Printed parts (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - The Supplicants, 21.
    Contents: I. Prologue; II. Anguish and Deliverance. According to the drafts, this work was conceived as "a Cantata for feminine choir and orchestra"
    - Drafts (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Full score manuscript (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Full score manuscript copies (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Printed parts (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Printed full score (Box 23, Folder 2)